Welcome to the Dark Malta Festival!
I'm back on Malta for the Dark Malta Festival because I just love the weather here, the location, the bands, the festival.
It is awesome. So let's come along and join me to interview some bands to dance a lot and just have a great time
for my Malta holiday
2026 let's go
So with me is Alex from Den Con Silence.
I just saw you on stage.
How was the gig?
It was fun and it was a great crowd and a very cool festival.
Because we heard of this place, never been here before.
Tiny island, you can drive from one point to the other end of the island in like 20
minutes.
and it's really hard to find on the map.
Like, where is Malta?
You have to try to zoom out and like, oh, there it is.
So yeah, but it's cute.
I've seen you on your tour, on festivals.
What is the difference between a festival setup and a tour setlist?
At the moment, I actually prefer festivals
because I can put more energy into one spot.
You know, like, let's do this show and put 100%.
Tour is exhausting because some days you wake up, maybe you're sore in your throat or you can be hangover.
It can be ups and downs, but festivals, I actually prefer festivals. I have more fun.
Alright, thank you so much.
See you then.
I'm a god of emotions
Now she knows what I feel
But she didn't say a word
Stood bare with a heart of steel
She doesn't know how much it hurts
Again my eyes run dry
Into the ocean I cry
Okay, two minutes before the show with exercise.
Let's do the pre-show preparations.
Yes. First, knees. Grab it. Not at the foot, but at the ankle.
Yes, yeah. Left. Other one. Yes.
Okay. Now stretch your back. Knee stays. Okay. Touch the ground. Yes, I touch the ground.
And now left. Okay. And right. Right. Other side. Other side. Ah!
Okay, and very important to play the call-bell.
Here.
Because for the perfect call-bell song you have to break your ankle.
Break your ankle?
Break your ankle.
Doesn't sound healthy.
Yeah, it's not healthy.
It's a call-bell.
Alright.
That's the pre-show routine.
Alright, let's go.
We'll be right back.
So I'm here with Das Ich.
Yes.
And you're at Malta.
At Malta.
Stefan and Sven.
And me.
You're three persons and call yourself Das Ich, which is one person.
No, well, the ego is having three parts.
Now you can guess who is who.
You're from Germany, as I am.
How did it come that you're playing at Malta?
That's a good question.
It's also for us the first time at Malta at the Dark Malta Festival and we just got the
invitation a year ago so we had been really happy and of course it's a bit like a vacation
so we came already on Friday and we're enjoying two days of beach so it was really awesome.
Beach!
What did you do at a beach at Goth People?
We are humans.
Yeah, we like beach.
Did you use 50 plus sunscreen?
Of course.
No, but actually I love this kind of weather, especially after winter time.
I mean, it's warm, but it's not so warm because it's quite windy.
So it's perfect for the goth people, not too hot.
You've been in the business a long time.
We've seen so many festivals like the old festivals in Germany, Mera Luna, Amphi, WGT, everything.
How is it to play at a relatively new festival where you've never been before?
Well, there's always popping and especially in the last years there were popping up a lot of new festivals.
And honestly, I'm always really happy because new festival also means new kind of crowd sometimes.
Of course here it is more like I would say people what you also see at the Amphi festival or so.
I saw a lot of Amphi t-shirts.
Yes, definitely. Therefore I refer on that.
But basically we love the small new festivals. There's a few in Germany and in other regions.
We're going now for a tour in the United States, also playing there some festival.
and it's always beautiful because you can reach out to new people,
sometimes young people who never have heard of you,
especially when you're so old like us.
But yeah, you're true.
We even remember the days really quite vividly
when Mira Luna was still called Cello Festival,
so we played like the first Cello Festival.
What is your plan for the future of the band,
being said that you're in a business for so many years already?
Staying alive!
going till die.
Till you die. Of course.
It's my dream
to just light up
on this cross when I'm hanging
on the singing goddess' throne.
Just in the moment,
burn, baby, burn.
And you must know, it's really a privilege.
I just was thinking about that
the last days. I mean,
this is really a beautiful holiday
location where people pay lots of money
to fly here, to have
hotel and so on.
And we are having this privileged life to just hang out here, getting even paid for doing this.
So there is nothing you can ever complain about.
Therefore, of course, we try to go on.
And we're really thankful that there is not only so many old followers who are fully supporting us by buying our records and merchandise.
It's also many young people.
And it was for us really beautiful with the last new album, Fanal.
because we suddenly we were first a bit afraid like how will be the response but
it was so awesome response and that was going so well so this gave us a lot of
motivation to go on and we're actually already again working on new tracks
mostly was very afraid because it took so long time and maybe the people forgot
us I wish you a lot of fun at the gig tonight and thank you thank you very
Thank you very much and support this great channel!
Attention! Attention! I'm coming!
You did some sightseeing already. What can you recommend to do on Malta?
First, the island Goso is awesome. There's an old ancient ruin. This was awesome for me and Valetta at night
Beautiful. I mean according to a song the sea I would say the sea
Yeah, it's a little bit cold, but it works. The sea in April is quite cold on Malta. I've been there
I was like nope, nope, nope. Beautiful country
I mean you've already played on several German festivals, like old school festivals. How was it to be a malta? Was there a difference?
I mean, I would say the biggest difference was playing an acoustic drum kit today, first time for Elionair.
Usually we play e-drums.
But I quite liked it. Yeah, it was great.
Especially because no one of us had his own instrument, so it was like a little surprise.
You borrowed the instruments?
Yeah, we borrowed the instruments so we came on stage and it was like,
oh let's see which keyboard do you have?
And this one was great!
And the same was with the drum set because, as you said, normally we play E-drums
and today it was acoustic but it sounded really great.
Great team here, great get-rigged-sound guy, everything perfect.
So, yeah, they made it easy for us.
So, did you play better without your original instruments?
I wouldn't say that.
Because normally we got a sound directly in the ears
and today we had a monitor sound.
So it was a bit strange.
Old school monitor sound.
It was a little bit difficult.
So I would say no.
But it was for not playing your own instrument, it was good.
The crowd was very international.
They are also shearing up and waving their hands like in our normal shows.
It was awesome.
The crowd here is awesome.
Yeah, definitely.
They're really, really nice, really friendly.
Yeah.
So happy you enjoyed it.
Hopefully we will be here one day again.
Well, you have to tell it to Rene, not me.
Okay.
But maybe he will see it.
I cried an ocean of fear
Because it gets worse and worse
Went through rivers of tears
And no one sees how much it hurts
All right, Rene, here we are again,
organizer of Dark Malta Festival.
We've seen each other like three years ago.
Three years ago, I think it was the last time, yeah.
How did the festival develop?
What would you say is the resume of the three years?
After three years, it developed very well now.
I mean, the crowd is increasing year by year.
Even the venue, we're trying to give it more,
a bigger look now.
I mean, we've changed the system of the entrance, bigger food court, the pool party is now it's like an establishment, you know, it's like year by year they're getting bigger.
We've increased also to other days because we're doing the pre-party on Thursday and also a boat party on Monday.
So it's like now it's a five day festival, it's not anymore a three day festival and people are coming from all over the world.
Yes, nice.
I noticed that the pool party is way bigger and that there are more people overall here.
That's right.
Yes. So what are your plans for the future?
There are some nice plans for the future.
I cannot until now announce anything.
The venue is already giving a hint what's going to be the future of Dark Malta.
So yes, we've got bigger plans coming in,
maybe also from next year for Dark Malta.
We're in the process of announcing some big headliners by the end of April,
so we're really looking forward for next year already.
because actually the work for next year started from last January.
I've talked to so many bands already and they all said it's so special to be here on Malta.
So why should bands come here and apply to play at the festival? What would you say?
I believe it's a different market. I mean, it's not like the other European festivals
because even the location by itself, it's a very exotic location.
The weather, you know, the country itself. I mean, it's April, it's already summer nearly.
So I mean even the crowd the energy is different because I'm in the warm weather
Everyone's relaxed everyone's
Exactly, everybody, you know come first go to the beach then they will come to the party
So there's a special energy going on also. Our crew is very very good
I mean it has been praised by all the bands after all their shows. So
We're really looking forward to have more new bands playing at dark walter and there will be more new bands playing at dark walter
So yes, so i'm so looking forward to the announcements until next year. Thanks so much. Thanks a lot. Thanks for coming again
It's the last day of my Malta trip and I'm doing a very quick photoshoot here by the
sea, but it's been another amazing trip here on this island and to dark Malta of course.
I am so happy that I was able to come back.
Thanks for watching.
Quite a few people approached me during the festival and told me that they're basically
here on the festival because they saw my YouTube videos in the previous years and that makes
me so glad and so happy.
So thanks for watching and if you thought, well, that is a great festival, then maybe
I'll see you next year.
Have a nice day.
Bye.